Placido Wang

Houston, TX 77084 | 832-386-5753 | placidow@gmail.com

Website: placidowang.com

Github: github.com/placidowang | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/placidowang | Blog: medium.com/@placidowang

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Web Developer experienced in JavaScript/React and Ruby on Rails and a background troubleshooting computer software and hardware issues. With my creative and analytical skills, I love building elegant, efficient solutions to everyday problems. I possess strong skills in problem-solving, critical thinking, adaptability, attention to detail, and teamwork that help software companies achieve their technology development goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, React.js, Hooks, Redux.js, Node.js, HTML5, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), jQuery, RESTful Webservices, API, JSON, Ruby on Rails, MVC, ActiveRecord, CRUD, Object Oriented Programming (OOP), SQL database, PostgresSQL, GitHub, Bash/Terminal, CLI

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Coup React - Github | Demo

Online version of the board game Coup

- Connected players online through PubNub channels to communicate actions and play against each other
- Developed a system to sync player game states inside Redux stores through PubNub data
- Utilized React to provide a clean and responsive web interface for players

League Tracker - Github | Demo

League of Legends account lookup tool and Champion database

- Used React to display info for 100+ Champions in an intuitive and responsive design
- Built a search feature for users to quickly sort and filter through Champions
- Gathered current Champion data from an API and seeded a database

Flight Guru - Github | Demo

Flight tracker that finds restaurants based on your flight number

- Utilized browser session and cookies to authenticate users to keep track of their specific flights
- Fetched flight and restaurant data from Aviation Stack API and Google Places API
- Created easy-to-use HTML/CSS pages with Ruby on Rails to maintain RESTful routes

EXPERIENCE

Smith & Associates, Houston, TX

07/2014 - 11/2019

Quality Control Specialist

- Inspected computer hardware and IC components in accordance to company certifications involving health and safety, quality control, and environmental standards
- Tested parts and recorded data to meet demands of clients from individual consumers to aerospace/military
- Verified integrity of parts with spec sheets and communicated with sales representatives and vendors if parts were suspicious

Quality Control Specialist - Contractor on Schlumberger Project

01/2017 - 03/2018

- Restored electronic component storage condition by filtering through entire stock, updating records on usable parts and discarding unusable parts
- Identified and salvaged usable obsolete integrated circuits, capacitors, resistors and other electronic components, which saved the company a significant amount in assets
- Created and implemented plan to properly store salvaged product, ensuring optimal long-term storage condition

EDUCATION

Flatiron School, Houston, TX

01/2020 - 05/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript/React Immersive Program

University of Texas at Dallas, Dallas, TX

08/2009 - 12/2011

Completed coursework towards a Bachelor of Science degree in Computer Engineering